Merrill Moore Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Subject File, circa 1920-1957 (Box D1-D219)
  - Military career (Box D135)
    - Army evaluations of medical articles
    - Army historical records
    - Army miscellaneous
    - Army records
    - Association of Military Surgeons
    - Atomic medicine (Box D136)
    - Award
    - AWOL pattern
    - Bernier, Joseph L.
    - Black, Robert L.
    - Blain, Daniel
    - Blatz, Katherine E.
    - Bliss, Raymond W.
    - Bornstein, Joseph H.
    - Boyd, Harriet M.
    - Caldwell, John M.
    - Camp, Edwards
    - Chandler, Alfred W.
    - Chinese decoration
    - Commendations
    - Commission
    - Crabtree, James A.
    - Craig, Winchell M.
    - Decorsey, Elbert
    - Duke, Raymond E.
    - Goriup, Othmar F.
    - Groesbeck, Bertram, Jr.
    - Grow, Malcolm C.
    - Hawley, Paul R.
    - Houle, Florynce M.
    - Hume, Edgar Erskin
    - Jahnes, William G.
    - Kester, Wayne O.
    - Knoblauch, Frederick J.
    - Liebolt, Frederick Lee
    - Lyon, George M.
    - McDaniel, Frederick L.
    - Mackin, James H.
    - Mead, Sedgwick
    - Miscellany
    - Miscellany (Box D137)
    - Orders
    - ORTSU, 1947, 1949-1951
      - Psychiatry
    - Parran, Thomas (Box D138)
    - Reserve education and training
    - Reserve training
    - Scheele, Leonard A
    - Soderberg, Bernard N.
    - “Some Neuropsychiatric Disorders”
    - Swanson, Clifford A.
    - 21st Evacuation Hospital
    - Vandel, Frederick
    - Van Slyke, Cassius, Jr.
    - Warren, Shields
    - Whayne, Tom F.
    - Yarbrough, O. D.
  - Milks, Mr. and Mrs. Harold
  - Miller, James F.
  - Miller, Mary Owings, 1953-1955
  - Milner, Rosamund
  - Milton, Fund
  - Miscellany (Box D139-D141)
    - 1936-1942
    - 1936-1942, 1946-1952 (Box D142)
    - 1950-1951, 1953-1954 (Box D143)
    - 1954-1956 (Box D144)
    - 1956, undated (Box D145)
    - Undated (Box D146)
  - Mitchell, Charles (Box D147)
  - MM Importing Co.
  - “The Modern Dance of Death”
  - Modern Gift Shop
  - “Moment in Jamaica”
  - Mongan, Sherry
  - Moore, Adam
  - Moore, Ann Leslie Nichol
  - Moore, Geoffrey
  - Moore, Helen Lane
  - Moore, John Trotwood
  - Moore, Mrs. John Trotwood
  - Moore, Mrs. John Trotwood (Box D148)
  - Moore, Mary Daniel
  - Moore, Merrill
    - Disposition of papers
    - Personal (Box D149)
  - Moore, Merrill D.
  - Moore, William Gillespie
  - More Clinical Sonnets, correspondence
  - Morrell, Diane
  - Morris, Frank
  - Morrissey, Ralph
  - Morse, A. Reynolds
  - Morton, Inez
  - Mosher Press
  - Mosley, Zack
  - Mott, Frank Luther
  - Mott, Stewart
  - Mounts, Charles Eugene
  - Mullen, John
  - Multiple sclerosis
  - Munn, James B.
  - Murrow, Edward R.
  - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, Mass.
  - “N” miscellaneous, 1936-1942, 1954-1957 (Box D150)
  - “Name It Yourself”
  - Narcotic license
  - Nashville, Tenn.
  - National Board of Medical Examiners
  - National Committee for an Effective Congress
  - National Economy League
  - National Research Council
  - Nationalist China
  - Nature magazine
  - New Bookstore and Gallery
  - New Directions
  - New England Journal of Medicine
  - New England Poetry Club
  - New England Society of Psychiatry
  - New England Telephone and Telegraph Co.
  - Newman, Israel
  - New Mexico Quarterly
  - New Orleans, La. (Box D151)
  - New Republic
  - New Year's Eve program, WGBH radio
  - New Yorker
  - New Zealand, 1951-1957
  - New Zealand (Box D152)
    - Basham family
    - Book on
    - Doctors
    - Garlick family
    - Libraries
    - Lumsdaine, Mrs. Arthur
    - Notes
    - Powell, A. W. B.
    - Psychiatrists
  - Newspaper reviewer
  - Newspapers
  - Newsweek
  - Nichol, Mrs. Adam G.
  - Nichot, Mrs. Georges
  - Niemann Fellows, Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass.
  - The Noise That Time Makes (Box D153)
  - Nolan, Mary U
  - Nursing homes for mental cases
  - Nut Club, 1953-1956
  - “O” miscellaneous, 1954-1957
  - Oberndorf, C. P.
  - Obligations
  - Occupations
  - O'Connell, Lenahan
  - Office management
  - Office supplies (Box D154)
  - Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio
  - Old Corner Book Store
  - “On the Writing of Poertry”
  - Operation Research Office
  - Opportunities for publication
  - Osborne, Edith Fitts
  - Osborne, Hope
  - Ossorio, Alfred
  - Oura, Sumiko
    - 1936-1942
    - 1936-1942 (Box D155)
    - 1936-1942, 1953-1954 (Box D156)
  - Overholser, Winfred, 1948-1949, 1951-1957
  - Owens, Olga
  - “P” miscellaneous
    - 1936-1942
    - 1936-1942, 1954-1957 (Box D157)
  - Packard, Frederick C.
  - Paebar Publishing Co.
  - Paef, Bashka
  - Palm Beach Times
  - Pandora
  - Parade of Youth, Inc.
  - Paraguay
  - Parker, Mother (Box D158)
  - Parker, Mrs. James A., 1951-1954
  - Partisan Review
  - Patt, Benny
  - Paul, John R.
  - Paxton, Hall
  - Pearce, Charles A., 1936-1942, 1951-1953
  - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1951-1954, 1956-1957
  - Pegasus Press
  - Pegler, Westbrook
  - Pei, Mario
  - Peltier, Kenneth E.
  - Pember, John E.
  - Periodicals
  - Pervitin
  - Peterson, Esther D.
  - Phalen, James M. (Box D159)
  - Phi Beta Kappa
  - Phillips, Roberta
  - Philosophical Library
  - Phoenix
  - Pictures
  - Pierpont, Donald W.
  - Pilgrim Broadcasting Co.
  - Pinckney, Josephine
  - Plastic Charts, Inc.
  - Pockwinse, Florence
  - “Poems for Poets”
  - Poems mailed for publication
  - Poems published in newspapers
  - Poetry
  - Poetry and Poverty
  - Poetry, blurb for a new book
  - Poetry magazine
  - Poetry Society of Virginia, 1953, 1956
  - Poets
  - Pokross, David R. (Box D160)
  - Pokross, William R.
  - Popek, Walter
  - Pornographic verse
  - Porter, Francis
  - Porter, Kenneth
  - Porty, Jane
  - Postgraduate medicine
  - Potter, Brooks
  - Pottery horse
  - Pouzzner, Bessie London
  - Powers, Ruth
  - Powers, Susan
  - Pratt, Henry
  - Press
  - Presscraft
  - Prichard, Merrill E.
  - Prince, Morton
  - Princeton University, Princeton, N.J.
  - Private support on research
  - Promotion and publicity
  - Property
  - Prose sketch
  - Prouty, Olive Higgins
  - The Provincial
  - Psychiatric Bulletin
  - Psychiatric conference (Box D161)
  - “A Psychiatrist's Book of Hours”
  - “Psychologic and Dynamic Features of the Sonnet Form”
  - Psychopathological Association meeting
  - Psychotherapy group
  - Publications, 1935, 1954
  - Publicity
  - Publishers' Weekly
  - Publishing service
  - Puerto Rican doctors
  - Putnam, Tracy
  - Pyetell, Carlton L.
  - “Q” miscellaneous, 1954-1955, 1957
  - “R” miscellaneous
    - 1936-1942
    - 1936-1942, 1954-1957 (Box D162)
  - Rabb, Alfred
  - Radio
  - Radio contacts, 1954-1956
  - Radio programs (Box D163)
  - Ramaga, Mary and Jean, 1936-1942, 1950-1954
  - Rand, Mrs. Stuart C.
  - Randall, Frances Ames
  - Ransom, John Crowe, 1938-1939, 1951-1952
  - Rayford, Julian Lee
  - Reading
  - Reading and studying
  - Register of sonnets
  - Reiter, Reuben
  - The Reporter
  - Requests to lecture
  - Rest homes
  - Reviews
  - Rich, Carrie R.
  - Richards, Laura E. (Box D164)
  - Richardson, Polly
  - Rider, Lillian D.
  - Riding, Laura
  - Riggs, Benjamin C.
  - Rinaker, Clarissa
  - Ritchey, John
  - Robb, Douglas, 1953, 1956-1957
  - Robertson, Imogene C.
  - Robie, Theodore R.
  - Robinson, Edward Arlington
  - Rodenhiser, Richard F.
  - Rodman, Selden
  - Rogers, Barbara, 1936-1942
  - Rogers, Frank Lee
    - 1948-1951
    - 1952-1954 (Box D165)
  - Romeike press clippings
  - Roosevelt, Curtis
  - Ross, David
  - Royalty
  - Rubin, Israel, 1955-1957
  - Rudd, Marguerite G.
  - Russell, Fred
  - “S” miscellaneous
    - 1936-1942
    - 1936-1942, 1954-1955 (Box D166)
    - 1956-1957 (Box D167)
  - Sachs, Hans
  - Sadler, Ralph
  - Safe deposit box
  - Saturday Review
  - Saul, Bernice
  - Schedules
  - Schering Corp.
  - Schoedler, Lillian
  - Schwab, Mrs. Robert
  - Science Service
  - Sea shell article
  - Sears, George (Box D168)
  - Selby, John
  - Selective Service
  - Seliger, Robert V.
  - “The Serviceman Who Drinks Too Much”
  - Seth Thomas Clocks
  - Sex and love poems
  - Shapiro, Kari
  - Sheean, Oliver
  - Shells, 1953-1956
  - Shenandoah magazine
  - Shirley, Joseph Chilton
  - Siegel, R. Lawrence
  - Sigma Chi fraternity
  - Sigma Chi magazine
  - Sigma Chi poems
  - Simon, Mr. and Mrs. Henry W.
  - Simons, Donald J.
  - Sind Medical Journal
  - Sitwell, Edith
  - Six Sides to a Man
    - Advertisement and corrections
    - Circulation
  - Slater, Max
  - Smith, Constance W.
  - Smith, Jackson A. (Box D169)
  - Smith, Kline & French Laboratories
  - Smith, Mrs. Watson
  - Social program for 1939
  - Solomon, Harry C.
  - “Some War poems”
  - Sonnets being circulated
  - Sonnets to be omitted from M
  - Souter, Gavin
  - Southern Literary Festival Association
  - Southern poets
  - Southern Psychiatric Association
  - Soviet correspondence
  - Spack, Allan, 1936-1942, 1953-1954 (Box D170)
  - Spanish music
  - Spanish translations
  - Speaking engagements, 1952
  - Spearhead magazine
  - Spears, Monroe K.
  - Speeches and lectures, 1931-1932, 1934
  - Speigel, Ernest A.
  - Springfield Indians
  - Squantum
    - Community planning
    - Employment
    - House
    - Lectures
  - Squire, Dorothy
  - Starr, Alfred, 1950-1955 (Box D171)
  - Starr, Cecile, 1950-1957
  - Starr, Henry
  - Starr, Milton, 1934-1939, 1954
  - Starr, Sara, 1952-1953
  - Steinberg, Jacob, 1951-1953
  - Stevens, Eleanor
  - Stevens, Paul (Box D172)
  - Stevens, Wallace
  - Stokes & Stockell, Inc.
  - Story-A-Day, Inc.
  - Straub, Carlyle
  - Strecker, Edward A.
  - Stribling, T. S.
  - Stuart, Jesse
  - Suma world language
  - Supplies ordered, 1951-1954
  - Survey of Massachusetts community psychiatric resources
  - Swallow, Alan
  - Sympathy messages
    - 1957
    - 1957 (Box D173)
  - Syphilis
  - “T” miscellaneous
    - 1936-1942, 1954-1956
    - 1957 (Box D174)
  - Tan, Kim H.
  - Tate, Allen
  - Taylor, Helen K.
  - Taylor, William S.
  - Teachers Insurance & Annuity Association of America
  - Tennessee State Board of Medicine
  - Therapy notes
  - Thimann, Joseph
  - Things to do
  - “The third Grade”
  - Thomas, Charles C.
    - 1951-1952, 1954-1956
    - 1956-1957 (Box D175)
    - Sonnets rejected by
    - Substitutions
    - Treatment of alcoholism
  - Tibbetts, Howard M.
  - Ticket list
  - Time center project
  - Tobey, Pauline, 1950-1953
  - Today's Health
  - Trevithick, Trevor
  - Trilling, Lionel
  - Trinity, Gunnetta
  - Trip instructions
  - Trotwood memorial
  - “The Truth about Married Love”
  - Tuftonian
  - Tuley, Henry Enos
  - Turner, W. P.
  - Twayne Publishers, 1954-1957 (Box D176)
  - “U” miscellaneous, 1954-1957
  - University Press
  - Untermeyer, Esther
  - Untermeyer, Jean Starr, 1936-1942, 1951-1952, 1956-1957
  - Untermeyer, Louis
    - 1935-1942
    - 1935-1942, 1951-1954, 1956-1957 (Box D177)
  - Untermeyer, Louise and Esther,1936-1942
  - “V” miscellaneous, 1936-1942, 1954-1957 (Box D178)
  - Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tenn.
  - Vanderbilt University School of Medicin, Nashville, Tenn.
  - Van Dine, S. S.
  - Veazey, George Ross
  - Vital statistics, Massachusetts, 1930
  - Vocarium discs, 1951-1953
  - Vocarium press notices
  - Voices
  - Vrooman, William T.
  - “W” miscellaneous (Box D179)
    - 1936-1942, 1954
    - 1955-1957 (Box D180)
  - Watchel, W. W.
  - Wagenhals, Margaret
  - Walsh, Liz
  - Walter, Muriel
  - “Waltzing Matilda”
  - War psychiatry (Box D181)
    - Air Force material
    - Alcoholic history
    - Army research project
    - Attitudes of neurotic soldiers
    - Baier, Lt. Col.
    - Bulk purchase index
    - Chief of Medical Service report
    - “The Chief Complaints of Neuropsychiatric Patients”
    - “The Chief Complaints of Neuropsychiatric Patients” (Box D182)
    - Cole, Nancy
    - Cole, Nancy (Box D183)
    - Complaints of neurotic soldiers
    - Consultation forms
    - Consultations with T. H. W.
    - Control of cluggers
    - Crane, James E.
    - Customs and courtesies
    - Disease control
    - Ditching incident
    - Drinking habits in air force personnel
    - Educational history (Box D184)
    - Elkind, Henry B.
    - Family histories
    - February report
    - “Fifty Mental Casualties”
    - Front sheets
    - “The Health of Combat Fliers”
    - Henderson, J. L.
    - Induction Board experience
    - Ink-blot test
    - Mass hysteria
    - Matthews
    - Maxwell, Reuben
    - Medical history
    - Mental deficiency
    - Mental hygiene paper for students at Fitzsimons, 1942 (Box D185)
    - Military history
    - Military law
    - Miscellany, (1 folder) (Box D186-D187)
      - Morale (Box D188)
    - Nervous history
    - Neuropsychiatric cases
      - 1944, Jan.-Mar.
      - 1944, May-Nov., undated (Box D189)
      - 13th Air Force (Box D190)
    - Neuropsychiatric work in an Army hospital
    - Notes
    - Notes of a battalion sugeon
    - Notes on a marine surgeon
    - Notes on operational fatigue
    - Outline for research writing
    - Psychiatric problems and morale
    - Psychiatric thesis
    - Psychiatry and surgery (Box D191)
    - Psychiatry in the army
    - Psychoneurosis
    - Psychoneurosis of war
    - Psychoneurotic soldiers
    - Recreational therapy
    - Return to combat
    - Shellshock
    - Shryrock, Henry S.
    - Skit on orders (Box D192)
    - Social history
    - “Soldiers Who Break Down”
    - Some notes on war
    - “Some observations on Neurotic Soldiers”
    - Special questions for Air Force personnel
    - Station hospital organization
    - “Ten Things They Impressed on Me”
    - Treatment
    - Two air force cases
    - Typical case history
    - War and psychiatry
    - Ward psychology
    - Whereett, Major
  - Washingtonian Hospital, Boston, Mass. (Box D193)
    - “A” miscellaneous
    - Abbott, John Adams
    - Abstinence, sudden
    - Acknowledgments of shell reprints
    - Adler, Raissa
    - Advisory board, draft service
    - Alcohol and alcoholism, legislation on
    - Alcoholic Consultation Bureau
    - Alcoholics Anonymous
    - Alcoholism
      - Cabot case
      - Diet
      - Drunken driving
      - Film
      - General
      - Humor
      - Lectures for colleges
      - Lectures for laymen
      - Letter to the Boston Herald
      - Mental problem (Box D194)
      - Post-acute stage
      - Present-day problem
      - Primer on
    - Alcoholism and the barbiturates
    - Alcoholism and cancer
    - Alcoholism in the army
    - Alcoholism in literature
    - “Alcoholism in Military Service”
    - Alexander, Leo
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science
    - American Journal of Psychiatry
    - American Medical Association
    - American Neurological Association
    - American Psychopathological Association
    - Application for commission in the army (Box D195)
    - Army and navy correspondence
    - “B” miscellaneous
    - Book preface notes
    - Book reviews
    - Boston City Hospital, Boston, Mass.
    - Boston Committee of Education on Alcoholism
    - Boston Medical Library, Boston, Mass.
    - Boston Society of Psychiatry and Neurology
    - Boston Sunday Advertiser
    - Bowman, Karl M.
    - Bradford and Spurling
    - Bradley, Charles
    - Bronze Star Medal Award
    - Buonanni, Filippo (1638-1725), article on
    - “Bus-Barcelona” miscellaneous (Box D196)
    - “C” miscellaneous
    - Carroll, Robert S.
    - Clapp, Charles
    - Coast Guard
    - Cole, Helen Moore
    - Committee to study proposal concerning sale of alcohol
    - Cyclopedia of Medicine and Surgery
    - “D” miscellaneous
    - Davenport, Charles B. (Box D197)
    - “Dawn”
    - Day, Hilbert F.
    - Deadly, Kathleen
    - DeCosta, Estelle
    - Diller, Theodore
    - Draftees, questions for
    - Drug addiction and intoxication symposium
    - Drug symposium
    - Dry League of America
    - Durfee, Charles H.
    - “E” miscellaneous (Box D198)
    - Ehrmann, Max
    - Entertainment
    - “F” miscellaneous
    - Fortune magazine
    - Freeman, Walter, and James W. Watts
    - Funds
    - “G” miscellaneous
    - Gardiner, Raynor M.
    - Graham, Otis L.
    - Gray, George W.
    - Gray, Mildred Geneva
    - Gregg, Alan
    - “H” miscellaneous (Box D199)
    - Haggard, Howard
    - Hamilton, George
    - “Hark, Now I Hear Them”
    - Hathaway, Kitty
    - “The Health of Combat Fliers”
    - Herman, Sue
    - History of liberalism in Japan
    - Holt, Rufus
    - Holy Cross College, Worcester, Mass.
    - Howard, Grace C.
    - “I” miscellaneous
    - Institute on Alcoholism
    - Investigations of alcohol problem
    - “J” miscellaneous
    - Jacoby Club
    - “K” miscellaneous (Box D200)
    - Kalak Water Co.
    - Kolb, Lawrence
    - Kuntz, Albert
    - “L” miscellaneous
    - Levine, Maurice
    - Library of Congress readings
    - Life & Health
    - Literary correspondence
    - Little, Amos R.
    - Little, Amos R. (Box D201)
    - Loring, John
    - “M” miscellaneous
    - “Mc” miscellaneous
    - McHenry, Joseph E.
    - Mackay, Wilson
    - Manary, James W.
    - Marston, Elizabeth R.
    - Massachusetts Fish and Game Association
    - Medical Correctional Association
    - Medical director
    - Medical directorship
    - Medical enrollment form
    - Medical societies
    - “Medico-Social Aspects of Alcoholism in War-Time”
    - Mental examinations
    - Merck, George W.
    - Metropolitan State Hospital, Waltham, Mass. (Box D202)
    - Miller, Martin H.
    - Miscellany, (1 folder) (Box D203)
    - Moore, Johnnie
    - Moore, Mrs. John T.
    - Moore, Mrs. Merrill
    - Morale activities
    - Movies
    - Myerson, Abraham
    - “N” miscellaneous
    - National Committee for Education on Alcoholism
    - National Committee on Alcohol Hygiene (Box D204)
    - National Good Templar
    - National Woman's Christian Temperance Union
    - “The Neurological Service at the Boston City Hospital”
    - Neurotic soldiers
    - New England Journal of Medicine
    - New Zealand book of poetry
    - Newman, A. Joseph
    - Newspaper publicity
    - Newton, Hazel
    - Nichol, Adam Gillespie
    - Norfolk Medical News
    - “O” miscellaneous
    - “One Morning with the Hermit Crab at Belleview”
    - Outpatient
    - Overholser, Winfred
    - “P” miscellaneous (Box D205)
    - Parsons, Talcott
    - “Phoenix,” correspondence on manuscript
    - Poet Physicians, correspondence on
    - Police information
    - Politics
    - “The Practice of Psychiatry,” correspondence on
    - “The Pragmatic Temper”
    - Project for a paper
    - “A Psychiatrist Looks at the Alcohol Problem”
    - “A Psychiatrist Looks at the Problem of Alcoholism”
    - “Psychiatry in Modern Life,” correspondence on
    - “Psychotherapy: Some Considerations”
    - Publicity
    - Pullen, Roscoe L.
    - Purchasing (Box D206)
    - Purple Heart award
    - “Q” miscellaneous
    - Quarterly Journal of Studies on Alcohol
    - Questionnaire on drinking
    - “R” miscellaneous
    - Radio broadcasts
    - Rakieten, Nathan
    - Ray, Marie Beynon
    - Reorganization of Washingtonian Hospital
    - Reprint list
    - Research
    - Research Council on Problems of Alcohol
      - General
      - Boston, Mass., members (Box D207)
      - Moore, Harry
      - Moore, Harry (Box D208)
      - Request for funds
    - Research projects
      - Brain waves
      - Clotting time
      - Emerson Drug Co.
      - Forbes, William
      - Loring, John
      - Metrazol
      - Nutrition
      - Smoke
      - Stotz, Elmer
      - Temperature
      - Trowbridge, Lowell S.
      - Vironamin
    - Resources
    - Rogers, Barbara
    - Rotary Club
    - “S” miscellaneous
    - Sachs, Hanns (Box D209)
    - Sarcka Ranch
    - Saturday Evening Post, proposed letter to
    - Schwengel, Frank R.
    - Scientific Temperance Federation
    - Seagram (Joseph E.) & Sons
    - Seliger, Robert V
    - Shellenberger, L. C.
    - Sigma Chi
    - “Snowy Owl Invasions”
    - Spack, Allan (Box D210)
    - Speaking appointments
    - Squantum property
    - “The Street Car Symphony”
    - “T” miscellaneous (Box D211)
    - Taxi drivers
    - Tennessee Historical Commission
    - Tests and examinations
    - Thayer, Hartley W.
    - Therapy
      - General
      - Electric shock
      - Psychotherapy
      - Thought-control class
    - Thomas, Charles C.
    - Timilty, Joseph F.
    - Trowbridge, Lowell S.
    - Trowbridge, Lowell S., and John Galt
    - Turner, Hill
    - “U” miscellaneous (Box D212)
    - Union Signal
    - United States Army, 1937-1938
    - United States Public Health Service
    - “V” miscellaneous
    - Vironamin project
    - “W” miscellaneous
    - Wayman, Dorothy
    - Wellcome Award
    - Wells, Henry W.
    - West, Villa T.
    - “What Gulls Do Not”
  - Waterman, George A. (Box D213)
    - May 1937-Sept. 1940
    - Oct. 1940-Aug. 1957 (Box D214)
    - Interview and biographical notes
    - Miscellaneous
  - Wedemeyer, Albert C., 1951-1954, 1956-1957 (Box D215)
    - References
    - References (Box D216)
  - Wells, Frederic L.
  - Wells, Henry
    - 1952
    - 1952-1957 (Box D217)
    - Miscellany (Box D218)
  - Weller, George
  - Wet Science Invades the Schools, review of
  - Whangaroa
  - “What I Believe”
  - Wheatley Parker
  - Whitaker, Mr. and Mrs. Thomas
  - Whitney, Elizabeth D.
  - Whitney, Mr. and Mrs. Joel, 1950-1951, 1953
  - Whittall, Gertrude, 1952-1956
  - Wilbar, George B.
  - Williams, William Carlos
  - Wills (Box D219)
  - Winchell, Walter
  - “Winged Dragon”
  - Witt, Guy F.
  - Wood, Dr. and Mrs. Benjamin S.
  - Wooten, Paul
  - Work in progress, 1955
  - Works Project Administration project
  - Wright, Albion
  - Writing plans
  - Wyle, Irene, 1936-1942
  - “X” miscellaneous, 1954
  - “Y” miscellaneous, 1955-1956
  - Yakovlev, P. I.
  - Yang, Shuan-Hsi
  - Young, Stark
  - Yuan, L. Z.
  - “Z” miscellaneous, 1955-1957
  - Ziegler, Edward E.
  - Zilboorg, Gregory
  - Zook, Nicholas
  - Zubin, Joseph
- Literary File, circa 1923-1958 (Box E1-E122)
  Holograph, typed, and printed sonnets, supplemented by poems, prose writings, published articles and books, and miscellaneous material.
  Approximately two-thirds of the material consists of sonnets organized under general titles by Moore and arranged chronologically. A partial index of individual sonnets follows this grouping. The remaining material, also largely sonnets, is arranged alphabetically by title, theme, or subject.
  - 1923, Jonquil Gold, (1 vol. and 1 folder) (Box E1)
  - 1924, Residuals, (1 vol.); (2 folders) (Box E2)
  - 1925
    - Eos, (3 vols.); (3 folders) (Box E3)
    - Sea-Gulls and Grey Water and Grey Sky, (1 vol. and 2 folders)
  - 1926, Sonnets written, (1 vol. and 1 folder) (Box E4)
  - 1927
    - Congress of Fowls, (1 vol. and 1 folder)
    - Duumvir, (1 vol. and 1 folder) (Box E5)
    - Finsternis
    - Finsternis (Box E6)
    - Land, Sea, and Sky-Scapes, (1 vol. and 4 folders)
  - 1928 (Box E7)
    - America I Love You, (4 folders)
    - Carmina, (1 vol.)
    - Chronos (Box E8)
    - The Dance of Death, 20th Century, (1 vol. and 3 folders); (3 folders) (Box E9)
    - If This Is Youth, (1 vol.)
    - More Sonnets in the American Tradition (Box E10)
    - Musing, (1 vol.); (2 folders) (Box E11)
    - Poetry of Ashes
    - Unrecorded Things, (1 vol. and 1 folder) (Box E12)
    - The Urgency of Twilight, (1 vol.)
  - 1929 (Box E13)
    - Bud Averit
    - The Noise That Time Makes
      - Typescript
      - Page proofs and galley proofs, (1 vol. and 6 folders) (Box E14)
      - Spanish translations, scrapbook of holograph sonnets inscribed to Ann Leslie Nichol Moore, and clippings on the theme of time, (1 vol. and 4 folders) (Box E15)
      - Reviews, a pamphlet containing foreword and reviews, and clippings on the theme of time, (2 vols.) (Box E16)
    - Sonnets and Poems Written, (6 folders) (Box E17)
  - 1930
    - Quickened to Sympathy, (1 vol.); (1 folder) (Box E18)
    - A Sonnet Gallery of American Portraits, (1 vol. and 1 folder)